<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
  <!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "../common/shared_entities.xml">
  %sharedents;
]>
<!--
The MIT License (MIT)

Copyright (c) 2014 Robert Winslow Dalpe

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
-->
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title>The Nation of &nation_name;</title>
  </info>
  <para>
    Here you will find information about &nation_name; and its major settlments that any 
    individual who lives in or has briefly researched the nation would know. Feel free to use 
    these sections to help build your characters and integrate them into the world. 
  </para>
  <para>
    &nation_name; was founded roughly 450 years ago when crusaders from a temple of
    Abadar in &meadows_nation; embarked on a mission to colonize the region. They swore a 
    holy oath that the new nation would be an exemplar of civilation and glory for centuries to 
    come. At that moment, they founded the &crusade_org; and dedicated themselves to the cause of
    sharing this glory with the world. To that end, they established a means of constructing and
    linking &portals;&mdash;magical gates which can be used to travel to and from &nation_name;.
    Immigrants to the new nation were slow to come at first, but they did arrive. And as they 
    arrived, they founded successful new lives in the bountiful valley of &valley_name;. Word 
    spread, and the population of &nation_name; grew exponentially as people from all over the 
    continent came to investigate this new wonder and found their expectations exceeded. It was 
    not long before the fledling nation became the hub of luxury, trade, and travel that it is 
    today.
  </para>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Modern Life in &nation_name;</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      In the heart of the valley of &valley_name;, protected by the forboding &mountain_range; to 
      the north and the unfathomable &rift; to the south, &nation_name; echoes with 
      a clarion call of opportunity. Low, rolling hills stretch across the
      landscape, and lush green forests intermingle with networks of towns and villages. 
      Occasionally, gleaming cities sit at the center of these networks, marking the terrain
      with intricate webs of road that connect settlements for miles around. Along the foothills of
      the &mountain_range;, frontier towns dot lands carved with snow-melt rivers that
      from the peaks above to empty into &valley_lake;.
    </para>
    <para>
      The abundance of the valley may provide, but ultimately the people of &nation_name; are its 
      lifeblood. Most citizens live and work in ostensibly simple villages, where they develop
      arable land and pull forth rich resources from the valley's mines. Their harvests flow
      inward toward the cities of the nation, where they supply insatiable craftsmen and 
      merchants who give &nation_name; its reputation as an economic and cultural superpower. In 
      return, the inner settlements provide ample public works, education, infrastructure, and other
      resources that allow the outland residents to specialize and thrive. All the while, brave
      and resourceful frontiersmen pave the way for others to follow in their footsteps and expand 
      the glory of the nation.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Religion in &nation_name;</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      &nation_name; was founded as part of an Abadarian religious crusade, and its roots are still 
      apparent to this day. Although the nation is not strictly aligned with any one deity, its 
      senate is composed of eighteen representatives from the most influential temples&mdash;be it
      influence through number of worshipers, wealth, or other means. Currently the temples of 
      Abadar, Shelyn, Cayden Cailean, Sarenrae, Pharasma, Iomedae, and Erastil hold senate 
      positions. The temple of Abadar has maintained major power in the city, and from the gilded
      halls of &abadar_temple; in &law_city; it oversees much of the nation's financial and legal
      well-being. Shelyn and Cayden Cailean both have large followings in &arts_city;, and their 
      temples&mdash;&shelyn_temple; and &cc_temple;&mdash;draw tourists and worshippers from
      far and wide.
    </para>
    <para>
      Iomedae's temple is the &police_hq; in &law_city; and much of the police force are devotees.
      Sarenrae, Pharasma, and Erastil enjoy large popular support from all around the nation for
      their public services and good works, but they do not maintain large shrines or temples in
      any one location. Many other faiths have worshippers in &nation_name;, and although they do 
      not hold prominent political power, Desna, Gozreh, Calistria, and Irori all have noteworthy 
      followings in various places around the country.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>The Government of &nation_name;</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Outwardly, the government of &nation_name; is composed of three parts: an Emperor, a Senate,
      and &HoRs;. The Emperor is an elected official rather than a supreme ruler. There is no term
      limit for an Emperor, but most choose to rule for twenty to twenty five years before stepping
      down. The Emperor holds the power to veto laws, act as the commander of the &police;, and also
      resolves tie votes in the Senate. The Senate comprises eighteen leaders chosen from and by the
      nation's most eminent temples, with each temple holding a number of positions corresponding 
      with their influence. Senators are solely responsible for ratifying laws, and they also have 
      the power to call for an immediate re-election of the Emperor. &HoRs; are officials elected
      every four years by the citizens of their districts. Legally, the &HoRs; have only three 
      powers: they elect the Emperor from one of their own, they are the only citizens, besides the
      Emperor, permitted to directly address a meeting of the Senate, and they may vote to forcibly
      remove Senators from office for life.
    </para>
    <sidebar>
      <info>
        <title>Who's in the Senate?</title>
      </info>
      <para>
        Currently, the temple of Abadar is allocated eight senate seats. Shelyn holds three, and
        Sarenrae and Cayden Cailean each hold two. Pharasma, Iomedae, and Erastil are all 
        represented, but each holds only one seat.
      </para>
    </sidebar>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>The Central Cities</title>
    </info>
    <section>
      <info>
        <title>Crent, City of Markets</title>
      </info>
      <para/>
      <section>
        <info>
          <title>Life in the City</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <info>
          <title>Places of Interest</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <info>
          <title>Government Officials</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <info>
        <title>Regunt, City of Laws</title>
      </info>
      <para/>
          <section>
        <info>
          <title>Life in the City</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <info>
          <title>Places of Interest</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <info>
          <title>Government Officials</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <info>
        <title>Oblectant, City of Arts</title>
      </info>
      <para/>
          <section>
        <info>
          <title>Life in the City</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <info>
          <title>Places of Interest</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <info>
          <title>Government Officials</title>
        </info>
        <para/>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>