<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section [
  <!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "../common/entities/global.ent">
  %sharedents;
]>
<!--
The MIT License (MIT)

Copyright (c) 2014 Robert Winslow Dalpe

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
-->
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title>Classes in &nation_name;</title>
  </info>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Barbarians</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      The civilized and well-kept lands of &nation_name; are inhospitable to barbarian tribes. 
      Barbarism and brutishness are frowned upon universally across the country, and
      many barbarians would find it a challenge to be welcomed or to fit in. As there are no
      naturally occurring tribes in the valley, most barbarians trace their origins elsewhere on the
      continent. In particular, they thrive in the blazing sands of &desert_kingdom; and
      in the gladiatorial pits of &cliffs_nation;. 
    </para>
    <para>
      In &desert_kingdom;, fire-blooded &firepeople; are the warriors of nomadic tribes who roam 
      the desert, never staying in one place for too long as they consider it their duty to 
      safeguard their home and its culture. Though they may feel the bloodlust of battle, many are 
      pragmatists and some fund the efforts of their tribes by working as mercenaries. Others 
      may be outcasts or seekers of gold and glory looking to start a new life in a land different 
      from what they have known.
    </para>
    <para>
      &cliffs_nation_person; barbarians frequently rise to great ranks in the warrior culture of 
      their homeland. There, where power and determination are revered, barbarians can live akin to
      nobility. However, feats of greatness must be constantly proven, and one can only rise so
      high without a worthy tale of one's own. To this end, many leave &cliffs_nation; to
      travel the continent in search of fame and honor. But for each glorified warrior, there are 
      many defeated ones in his wake, and some among them are barbarians looking to redeem their 
      names in a new land. 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Bards</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      As a cultural capital, &nation_name;&mdash;and in particular the central cities&mdash;holds 
      performance and entertainment in high esteem and demand. One of the central cities, 
      &arts_city;, is completely dedicated to the betterment and enjoyment of the arts, and any
      performer, new or veteran, will find opportunity there. From frenetic street festivals, to
      the studious halls of &arts_college;, to the crystalline elegance of the &amphitheater; 
      amphitheater, there is no limit to the passions of &arts_city;'s citizens. This intensity has 
      even produced a saying known throughout the nation: no great performer will forever die so 
      long as there is music in &arts_city;. 
    </para>
    <para>
      Even outside of &arts_city;, a performer has many opportunities to excel. Politicians, 
      storeowners, and merchant guilds are all keenly aware of the impact a charismatic face can
      have on one's audience, and many seek the services of skilled spokesmen. Travelers, far
      from their homes, find comfort in local song and art even in a land so distant. And a rural
      life may become grim indeed without wanderers who tell tales or sing songs of grand 
      excitement and adventure.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Clerics</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Although outwardly &nation_name; may seem thoroughly secular and unaffiliated, its history and
      government are steeped in religion, and many faiths have large temples and congregations here.
      The temples of Abadar, Shelyn, and Cayden Cailean hold particularly strong
      political influence, and many of their clerics become officiaries in the grand courts of 
      &law_city; or the wild streets of &arts_city;. But for every cleric who wields the might of 
      cities, there are a thousand others dedicated to more personal endeavors. 
    </para>
    <para>
      Clerics of many faiths, but especially of Sarenrae, Pharasma, and Erastil, roam the cities and
      countryside performing good works and aiding public services. Some heed a call to protect 
      their loved ones, and join the &police;&mdash;a calling often heard by the faithful of 
      Iomedae. Others still seek scholarship in the &library; or &arts_college;, or to study the 
      mysterious and powerful relic shrines that dot the country.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Druids</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      The bounteous lands of the valley of &valley_name; are full of marvelous phenonmena and natural
      resources, and there is great need for those who would steward those resources correctly. 
      As a result, the druidic population of &nation_name; is not just composed of local druids, but
      also of those who have traveled long distances to experience the wonders of the valley. In
      particular, the nation has a considerable influx of druids from &forest_nation; even those of
      the reclusive &beast_tribes;. Once in the country, druids tend to pursue their own
      goals as wanderers, members of a druidic micro-community, or even as members of larger 
      organizations for&mdash;or perhaps against&mdash;the government.
    </para>
    <para>
      The druidic micro-communities are groups of druids that tend to gather together at sites of
      particular spiritual significance. There, they tend to flora and fauna of the area and ensure
      that the site is preserved against any who would do it harm. The &falls_druids; are especially 
      well known to locals and tourists for their protection of the &falls; area, and are perhaps 
      more famous than the druids would like.
    </para>
    <para>
      Druids that are members of larger organizations tend to work with a temple or the government.
      There they perform local functions such as ensuring that the harbors and rivers are 
      maintained, and giving advance warning for weather. They may also act as members of 
      committees that perform environmental advisories and studies for government projects. Not all
      organizations are so friendly towards the smooth operation of local and national government,
      however. One particularly infamous group, known as the &bad_druids;, are publicly a pro-nature
      lobbying group, but are widely known to perform anti-civilization acts such as magically
      weakening the foundations of buildings, defacing directories and road signs, and planting 
      trees in non-designated zones.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Fighters</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Martial prowess is a much sought after skill in &nation_name; and those who are gifted will
      find many opportunities to display their strengths. Although there is no formal army, the
      &police; is always looking for those of sharp mind and strong arm to help keep the 
      peace. Because of their limited manpower, the police have learned to fight smart, and they
      employ a wide range of skilled combat researchers and engineers to develop new tactics and
      equipment. Fighters looking to earn more than the govnerment is willing to pay might prefer
      to take on the role of bodyguard or strongman for a wealthy noble or shop owner. Others still
      may prefer to take a riskier path and bring their feats to the stage as combat performers
      &mdash;masquerading their deadly arts as performance pieces or sport in the &stadium; in
      &arts_city;. Outside of the central cities, those skilled in combat and with good knowledge 
      of the land excel as hunters or guards for villages and trade caravans. 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Monks</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Monks seeking purification and enlightenment through order and community may find themselves 
      at home in the central cities. There they have the opportunity to participate as good 
      samaritans via public works. There is only one official monk sect in the nation, the 
      &monk_sect;. They are a sect sworn to poverty and truth. In addition to the good works they 
      do for the communities around the country, they also act as a counter-lobby to the economic 
      elite of &nation_name;. Although there is only one official sect, many of the librarians in
      the &library; are monks who worship Irori. Regardless of affiliation, martial skill and spiritual 
      leadership are valued traits all around the nation. Whether as enforcers for the &police;,
      covert bodyguards, performers, or guides for those who wander from the path to enlightenment,
      a monk will not find herself without a purpose for long.
    </para>
    <mediaobject role="half-image">
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata format="SVG" width="100%" scalefit="1" fileref="https://googledrive.com/host/0B7b9uMyuu5dveGVfNTNqYldJZmc" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Paladins</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Although the nation was founded as the result of a crusade, its economic and political success
      have made the environment less than welcoming for holy knights. Paladins are seen by many
      government and mercantile leaders as unpredictable and potentially disruptive zealots who 
      might damage the smooth functioning of the nation. Even among the temples represented in the
      senate, most choose to call their paladins to other parts of the world. However, there are
      many causes worthy of advancement in &nation_name;, and those who can adhere to more 
      tolerant or flexible codes will often find their efforts rewarded. In particular, paladins of 
      Sarenrae and Erastil are often welcomed with open arms for their efforts to be understanding
      and mend the sufferings of the people. Some members of the &police; are also paladins of
      Iomedae, and they snuff out crime and corruption with zeal&mdash;though always under the 
      careful guidance of their superiors.
    </para>
    <para>
      But despite the best efforts of the nation's leadership to keep the zealots away, they are not
      always so successful. There are occasional instances of activism from both clandestine and 
      public groups of divine warriors who vie for greater recognition and political influence for
      their causes.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Rangers</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Although the valley of &valley_name; is relatively small and geographially isolated, much of
      its lands have yet to be tamed and its mines have yet to be fully charted. The wilds can be 
      dangerous, and as the people of &nation_name; forge ever outwards and downwards they are in
      need of those who can provide guidance through the unknown perils. Explorers and hunters ply
      the forests and mountains for quarry of bear, wolves, mountain lions, or perhaps an
      Aurumvorax caught feasting on a surface ore vein. The brave or foolhardy willing to 
      delve deep into the caverns below the nation on behalf mining operations may find foes 
      stranger still, but great bounty awaits those who fulfull their duties successfully. 
    </para>
    <para>
      In the parts of the country fresh with civilization, seasoned woodsmen and outland police 
      patrols protect fledgling villages and secure survival from season to season. And in the 
      heart of the country, those with connections to the wilds can deal in lucrative exotic pelts, 
      trophies, and other goods. For those who do not wish to exploit their talents for profit from 
      slaughter, there are many men, women, and children who will pay handsomly to see talented 
      animals and their trainers perform in &arts_city;.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Rogues</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Although the central cities are lawful and safe places, a rogue's talents are nonetheless 
      very useful. Merchants and politicians alike can always find a role for someone with
      quick hands and silent feet, and in a land of tourism and commerce pickpockets and con 
      artists have ample choice of targets if they're willing to take the risk. Some reformed
      scoundrels might choose to redeem themselves as bounty hunters or undercover agents for the
      &police;. Others instead opt to live as performers&mdash;bringing joy and
      excitement instead of aggravation and ruin. The &knife_throwers; is particularly well known 
      for taking in those of dubious pasts and repurposing them to more gainful employment as 
      daring, skillful daredevils.
    </para>
    <para>
      Outside of the central cities, rural life provides fewer opportunities for a rogue, and
      those who cannot or will not make livings as trappers or hunters often turn to criminal
      undertakings.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Sorcerers</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Opportunities of all kinds can appear unexpectedly in &nation_name;, and a sorcerer's 
      innate ability to instanly access the full wealth of her magical strengths is an invaluable 
      tool for responding to sudden windfalls. In the bustling central cities, sorcerers
      are valued as enchanters in crafting workshops, but they are especially valued in &arts_city;. 
      There, the constantly changing environment of festivals and performances often demands
      immediate response to crazy schemes and outlandish requests. A company of sorcerers known as 
      &fireworks_co; has specialized in this field, and keeps a sizable retinue of magical adepts on
      retainer for hire by performers in need. 
    </para>
    <para>
      A sorcerer's natural force of personality also benefits those who choose to employ their 
      powers to further some goal beyond wealth and entertainment. Many sorcerers of celestial and
      infernal bloodlines take leadership positions both in local government and mercantile 
      operations, where they excel in bringing allies and adversaries under their sway. Others still
      choose to unleash the full extent of their potential as members of the &police;.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Wizards</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      The vast libraries and combined cultural knowledge of the central cities are a great resource to
      many wizards, and none will struggle to find employment here. The government of &nation_name;
      employs a huge number of wizards in the &customs_dept;, where they research and approve requests for 
      transit using the country's magical gates. This approval process also involves the charging of 
      keys for the gates and their tranmission to the proper recipients. In exchange for their
      services and loyalties, the &customs_dept; funds research grants for these wizards and also 
      provides shelter and workspaces.
    </para>
    <para>
      Craftsman also value skilled wizards, and many vie to employ the best in their 
      workshops. For those who cannot afford a full time enchanter, supply shops offer the end 
      results of the creative process. &magic_supply; is a particularly well known name in 
      &market_city;, and they employ skilled enchanters to fulfill bulk and custom requests for 
      their clients.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>