<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section [
  <!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "../common/entities/global.ent">
  %sharedents;
]>
<!--
The MIT License (MIT)

Copyright (c) 2014 Robert Winslow Dalpe

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
-->
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title>Character Traits</title>
  </info>
  <para>
    Character traits are short summaries about your character's history, motivations, or 
    personality. They provide a few quick blurbs about overarching concepts for your character, and
    reward you with mechanical benefits for defining these concepts. In addition to providing you,
    the player, with ideas they also serve to help other players and the GM understand each other 
    and how the party might integrate.
  </para>
  <para>
    You may choose two character traits at the start of the scenario. You may not choose the same
    trait twice. Combat, Equipment, Faith, Magic, Race, Regional, Religion, and Social traits are
    not listed in this guide and should be taken from other material if you wish to use them. This
    guide defines only Campaign traits.
  </para>
  <para>
    In addition to your character traits, your party should also work together to establish a preexisting
    connection between your character and at least one other party member. Try to spread out these
    connections as much as possible between the members of the group. This will give the group
    a level of cohesion and reason for sticking together rather than working alone. Remember, you can
    always ask your GM for assistance with establishing traits and bonds between characters.
  </para>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Campaign Traits</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Campaign traits are character traits that are guaranteed to be integrated with some part of
      the scenario's storyline. They provide you with a surefire way to tie your character into the 
      story and seed your thoughts with ideas for character motivation and history. To accomplish
      this, they are much more prescriptive than other types of traits. You do not have to choose
      a campaign trait as one of your two character traits, but if you don't you should be sure to
      discuss your character with your GM so that she can plan out how to involve your character 
      with the story.
    </para>
    <para>
      It bears repeating that no matter what traits you choose, you should always strive to 
      establish an existing connection with at least one other character in the party before play 
      begins. Campaign traits are a fast and effective way to do this, but are not the only way.
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>Attacked by Gnolls</title>
      <para>
        You were attacked by a band of gnolls recently in your life, and now you harbor a deep, 
        burning hatred for the monsters. Perhaps your village was ransacked, and though you were 
        not killed&mdash;due to either resourcefulness or maybe blind luck&mdash;many of your 
        friends and loved ones were. Or perhaps your caravan was attacked on the road and you lost
        your belongings or close companions to the gnollish bandits. Whatever the situation, you've
        had something dear stripped from you, and your dreams are haunted by cackles and barks in
        the night. You've sworn to yourself that no Gnoll will escape from you alive from this day 
        on, and you've taken to studying them with malicious fervor.
      </para>
      <para>
        You may choose one of the following trait bonuses:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You receive a +2 trait bonus to Perception checks made to keep watch.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Add Abyssal (cannot speak) and Gnollish to your list of languages.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Shadows of the Past</title>
      <para>
        Someone, or multiple people, dear to you have been forcibly taken away before your eyes by
        sinister figures in dark cloaks. They may have come during the night and burst into your
        home, or their actions may have taken place in a secluded area in broad daylight. Wherever
        you were, they were very careful to simply prevent you from disrupting them rather than
        kill you or abduct you as well. The police have found no leads for your claim, and since 
        that moment, you have not seen nor heard of those who were taken. You haven't given up, 
        though, and recently you have turned up rumors that others have gone missing as well. 
      </para>
      <para>
        You may choose one of the following trait bonuses:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You receive a+1 trait bonus to all saving throws against fear spells and effects when an 
            ally within 30 feet is threatened.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Pick one of the following skills: Knowledge (local), Diplomacy, Intimidate, Disguise, or
            Sense Motive. You receive a +1 trait bonus to that skill, and that skill is considered a 
            class skill for you.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Driven Out of Business</title>
      <para>
        You once had a profitable enterprise, but were driven out of business by a shady competitor.
        Your competitor sprang out of nowhere, and his store was unusually well stocked and 
        equipped. Word of it spread surprisingly quickly, and at the same time so did rumors which 
        tarnished your reputation. Your suppliers became less and less reliable, and before long, 
        even your most loyal customers had stopped patronizing your business. The damage dealt to 
        your image was so severe that you have been unable to find any way to start again in the 
        commercial world. You're certain that this sleazy rival was involved in the destruction of
        your fortune, but you haven't found any way to prove it yet.
      </para>
      <para>
        You may choose one of the following trait bonuses:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist spacing="compact">
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Pick either charms or compulsions. You receive a +1 trait bonus to all saving throws against 
            spells and effects of that type while you and your allies are not in combat.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Pick one of the following skills: Bluff, Disable Device, Linguistics, Sense Motive, or
            Sleight of Hand. You receive a +1 trait bonus to that skill, and that skill is considered 
            a class skill for you.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>