<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section [
  <!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "../common/entities/global.ent">
  %sharedents;
]>
<!--
The MIT License (MIT)

Copyright (c) 2014 Robert Winslow Dalpe

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
-->
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title>The Central Cities</title>
  </info>
  <para>
    The Central Cities are the largest urban centers in &nation_name;. They
    represent the peak of culture and progress in the nation, and each of
    them has developed their own unique culture and specialties over time.
  </para>
  <sidebar>
    <info>
      <title>Common Government Resources</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Although they may not be specifically called out in these sections, you
      can expect most government agencies that deal with infrastructure to 
      have representation in all large settlements. This includes, but is not
      limited to, divisions such as the &police;, &public_works;, and other 
      servants of the common good.
    </para>
  </sidebar>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>&arts_city;, City of Arts</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Brimming with life and activity, the city of &arts_city; is the 
      veritable pulse of &nation_name;. Artists and entertainers from all 
      walks of life flock to the city to join in the cultural melting pot and
      experience the wealth &arts_city; has to offer. Anywhere is a stage, and
      revelry spills out into the streets, infusing the city with a constant 
      state of festivity. Each day could bring new celebrations replete with 
      performances and displays unlike any seen before it. As a result, 
      &arts_city; is a hot spot for tourists from around the world, and their
      presence ensures that there is plenty of gold to keep the entertainers
      at their antics. 
    </para>
    <mediaobject role="half-image">
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata format="SVG" width="100%" scalefit="1" fileref="https://googledrive.com/host/0B7b9uMyuu5dvNDZRUk5fSk1ZaGM" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>
      Officials long gave up on imposing bureaucracy upon the citizens, and 
      now simply seek to ensure that the city runs smoothly from one 
      performance to the next. The last vestige of control the government 
      maintains over the celebrations is the &festival_agency;, which 
      stages city-wide festivals, schedules access to large venues such as 
      &stadium;, and provides publicity for ambitious performers. The &police; 
      patrols the streets, keeping the city safe for residents and tourists 
      alike, but their presence is understated and does not impinge on the 
      city's carefree atmosphere. Petty crime is uncommon, and offenders are 
      swiftly swept to the nearest police station or courthouse for judgement.
    </para>
    <para>
      Despite the apparent laissez-faire attitude of the government,
      &arts_city; is extremely well-maintained. Buildings of sturdy wood and
      cut stone stand strong against the neverending flow of residents, and
      paved streets make for easy transport around the city. Lights both
      magical and mundane line the streets and buildings, vying for the 
      attention of passersby. Even with messy tourists who care not for the 
      city's cleanliness, strong sewers and trash removal systems sweep away 
      the filth and leave the city ready for the festivities to continue.
    </para>
    <section>
      <info>
        <title>Places of Interest</title>
      </info>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&amphitheater;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Rows of enormous amethyst crystals jutting from the entrance 
              give &arts_city;'s premier amphitheater it's name. Although its 
              appearance and sublime acoustics would suggest a man-made 
              structure, &amphitheater; is actually a naturally occurring
              geode phenomenon. Performing even once in the &amphitheater; is 
              the goal of many artists, and competition is fierce. The revered
              &auditioners; are the final elite arbiters of who will be graced
              by the stage.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&shelyn_temple;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Vivid botanical gardens and serene marble galleries compose the
              nation's premier temple of Shelyn. The temple is built on the 
              edge of the city and situated near the &amphitheater; so that the 
              clergy may more easily tend to the amphitheater. Compared to the 
              intensity of the city, &shelyn_temple; is truly a sanctuary for 
              those who wish to reflect upon the spiritual impact of the arts. 
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&arts_college;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              &arts_college; is one of the world's most prestigious schools for 
              the fine arts, and a central location for both prospective students
              and tourists alike. Although its intimidating spires, sharply slanted
              rooftops, and aged stone walls cast an imposing shadow, they belie
              the energy within. Its campus buzzes jovially at all hours of the 
              day as some of the greatest creative geniuses from around the 
              globe hone their skills.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&stadium;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Named for the carpet of small purple flowers that blooms in the 
              spring, the &stadium; is an expansive, open-air park and a prime
              location for many public events. Complete with several small 
              venues for performances as well as a large stadium, the 
              &stadium; boasts ample space and seating for tourists and citizens
              alike. Whether it be music, sports, or festivals, an event in the
              &stadium; is sure to be lively and draw a large crowd.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&bridge;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Spanning the &arts_city_river; River and joining the east and west
              of &arts_city; together, the &bridge; is more than just an 
              important piece of infrastructure. Many bits of &arts_city; 
              culture have incoporated the &bridge;, from tossing flowers into 
              the river below for good luck to being a hotspot for watching
              fireworks. More practically, it's also a natural chokepoint for 
              traffic through the city and its wide stone path is filled with 
              street performers, each trying to take advantage of their captive 
              audiences.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&cc_temple;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              A large stone carving of a frothing mug adorns the facade of
              &arts_city;'s favorite temple to the god of drinking and 
              merriment. This multi-story wood and stone building radiates a 
              warmth and festivity that can be felt from blocks away. The temple 
              hosts a stage and doubles as both a comedy house and theater for 
              celebrations of bravey, and its walls reverberate with laughter
              and cheers. To the confusion of tourists and the amusement of 
              locals, the interior of the temple is themed as a bank.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&arts_city_tourist_district;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Surrounding &arts_city;'s central plazas, this bustling
              district is a hotspot for tourism and revelry. Although
              most come to the district to be at the center of the 
              city's constant festivals, the competition between 
              enterprises to garner attention has changed the district 
              into a spectacle in its own right. Themed businesses, 
              wild street performers, and garish decorations all lend a
              hand in creating the district's unique atmosphere.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&arts_city_college_district;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Fed by the youthful, creative energies of the
              &arts_college;, the &arts_city_college_district; is the
              premiere place to scout rising talent and share ideas in
              the city. Although not as upscale as some parts of 
              &arts_city;, the inhabitants of the district are jovial
              and create a welcoming atmosphere. Collaboration and
              competition go hand-in-hand here, and it's very likely to
              see spontaneous performances erupt in the persuit of great
              art.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&arts_city_rich_district;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Mostly separated from the hustle and bustle of the city,
              the &arts_city_rich_district; provides a serene place for
              those who can afford it. Residents and visitors enjoy
              beautiful courtyards, spotless streets, and exclusively 
              close access to iconic locations such as &amphitheater; 
              and &shelyn_temple;.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&arts_city_poor_district;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              To call &arts_city_poor_district; a slum would be 
              disingenuous, but compared to the rest of &arts_city; 
              this district falls behind in upkeep and cleanliness.
              Tenement housing is plentiful, and in lieu of access to
              more fanciful pursuits, the residents of
              &arts_city_poor_district; excel in vice entertainment.
              Seedy bars and brothels adorn the streets, and the venues
              host bawdy and burlesque performances too vulgar for
              popular taste.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&arts_city_govt_district;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Tucked away in a less-noticeable portion of the city,
              &arts_city_govt_district; houses offices and storage 
              for government agencies such as the &police; and
              &festival_agency;.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&arts_city_quality_district;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Many master craftsmen who outfit &arts_city; with 
              superior quality instruments and supplies base their
              workshops in &arts_city_quality_district;. These great 
              makers demand a particular environment for their work, and
              the district has molded to reflect their tastes. Simple, 
              refined architecture and narrow cobbled streets give the 
              district a historic atmosphere, and even the wildest of 
              locals calm themselves out of respect when in the area. 
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>&market_city;, City of Markets</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Words and noise blend with the clink of coins in the vibrant market city
      of &market_city;. Known for its unparalleled selection of exotic goods,
      which harken both to cultures from around the world and at the same time
      something completely original, &market_city; is a haven for craftsmen.
      The best of the best travel here to study with other masters from all
      around. The result is a forge of rivalries and collaborations which
      drive the innovations of these ambitious creators ever foward. Their work
      and success have brought incredibly reknown to  both &market_city; and the
      nation as a whole, and wealth naturally flows to the city in the form of 
      hardened merchants and more casual buyers.
    </para>
    <para>
      The siren call of wealth and skill brings along with it much more strict
      government oversight. Left to their own devices, foreign merchants would
      surely bleed the country dry. In response, agencies such as the &customs_dept; and
      the &labor_dept; keep close watch on the conditions of the city. Given
      the amount of coin that flows through the streets, the &police; are
      omnipresent in &market_city;, ensuring that the city retains its name as a
      safe and reputable haven for trade. 
    </para>
    <mediaobject role="half-image">
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata format="SVG" width="100%" scalefit="1" fileref="https://googledrive.com/host/0B7b9uMyuu5dvR3FwWEt6bW5UNmc" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <para>
      The master craftsmen themselves are no pushovers either. Crafting guilds
      are strictly forbidden both in a legal sense and a communal one, as each
      individual crafter vies for the reputation of her own name. Consequently,
      mutual respect&mdash;even among the most obvious of rivals&mdash;is 
      paramount and palpable in the transactions that take place here.
    </para>
    <para>
      To feed the high demand of buyers, &market_city; has built itself up 
      around a system of attractive and efficient roads and neighborhoods.
      No space is wasted in thoroughfares large or small, as every bit of
      available wall space is transformed into a storefront or workshop. Sturdy stone
      buildings resist wear from unending shoppers, but also from nature's harshness
      and the occasional workshop fire. Goods transit smoothly through the 
      city's wide, paved streets, their navigation made easy by numerous road 
      markers. At night, hanging iron lamps illuminate the city's famous 
      twenty-four hour markets.
    </para>
    <section>
      <info>
        <title>Places of Interest</title>
      </info>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&grand_bazaar;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Thousands of shoppers browse the rows of tents 
              that fill this enormous open-air market. As one of 
              &market_city;'s internationally iconic features, the 
              &grand_bazaar; is home to all sorts of novelties and
              unique items. Although locally regarded as more for show
              than function, it is not unheard of to find true treasures
              nestled in the wares here. 
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&market_house;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Dozens of imposing wooden boards line the walls of this
              large forum, each filled with statistics and
              predictions for various market goods. Harried merchant 
              apprentices hustle along the walls with tablets and chalk
              in an unending effort to keep the boards up to date.
              Meanwhile, cold faced merchants and crafters eye the ever
              changing boards like vipers ready to strike.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&elven_enclave;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              &elven_enclave; is &nation_name;'s largest single home of 
              elves. Here they have fostered a small forest grove and 
              made their homes in its trunks and boughs. Elves, 
              Half-Elves, and fey races are openly welcomed, but most 
              others find themselves loosely tolerated as permanent 
              residents.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&dwarven_enclave;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Not to be outdone by the forest of &elven_enclave;
              or the cut stone of &market_city; itself, the Dwarves
              constructed a miniature mountainscape out of boulders
              from the nation's mines. Now complete complete with carved
              homes and bold designs, &dwarven_enclave; is a colony in
              its own right. Although legally no citizen may be 
              forbidden residence here, most non-Dwarves find the stony,
              cramped interior unwelcoming.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Lakeside Docks</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&arts_city_river; River Customs</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>&law_city;, City of Laws</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      At the heart of &nation_name; is the nation's crown jewel: the
      capital city of &law_city;. Towering, gleaming buildings of marble
      and polished stone strike a grand vista for those who first
      lay eyes upon the city. Impressive grids of streets and avenues 
      bustle with activity, feeding the machine that runs the nation.
      At night, although the streets die down to dim illumination by
      heavy iron lamps, the work of the city does not cease. Buildings
      big and small come to life as interior lights shine through their
      windows, offering tantalizing hints at the ongoings within.
    </para>
    <para>
      From first sight to last, &law_city; whisks away newcomers and 
      locals alike into an embrace of structure and control that seems 
      almost caring. The city runs like clockwork, with each inhabitant 
      and agency fulfilling a purpose in a timely and efficient manner. 
      From the lowliest courier to the highest seats of government, 
      every citizen of &law_city; is devoted fully to their cause. To do
      otherwise would be to invite certain scorn and disdain from one's 
      peers.
    </para>
    <para>
      Just as each citizen is devoted to their tasks, so is the city itself
      devoted to the law. Law is born and dies in &law_city;. Every 
      agency houses its highest offices here in this locus of government power.
      Yet despite the proximity of government control, the city does not
      quake under the tyranny of authoritarianism. That the government
      serves its people is a well respected fact, and it is commonly
      understood that &law_city; only functions at the willing 
      compliance of its citizens.
    </para>
    <section>
      <info>
        <title>Places of Interest</title>
      </info>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Capitol Building</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Temple of Abadar</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Merchant Guild Headquarters</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>University of Law and Business</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&library;</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>&police; Headquarters</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Lakeside Docks</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Emperor's Home</term>
          <listitem>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <mediaobject role="full-image">
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata format="SVG" width="100%" scalefit="1" fileref="https://googledrive.com/host/0B7b9uMyuu5dvM3o3aElWdTJTaGc" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>