<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
  <!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "../common/shared_entities.xml">
  %sharedents;
]>
<!--
The MIT License (MIT)

Copyright (c) 2014 Robert Winslow Dalpe

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
-->
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title>Races in &nation_name;</title>
  </info>
  <sidebar>
    <para>
      Due to the high economic and entertainment specialties of &nation_name;, it draws craftsman
      and tourists from all over the world.
    </para>
  </sidebar>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Humans</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Humans are the dominant race in the central cities and in the nation at large, despite the 
      generally high levels of diversity in the country. Humans native to &nation_name;
      are represented in all professions, and tend to hold the majority of influential positions 
      both in the economic and political spheres. They can be found in every major city and in the
      outlying areas of the country.
    </para> 
    <para>
      Humans hailing from other parts of the continent tend to come to &nation_name; for
      more specialized reasons. Farmers, clerics on pilgrimage, and visiting aristocrats from 
      &meadows_nation; are all common sights. The goat-riding &mountainmen; 
      from the peaks of &mountains_nation;
      are more rare, but sometimes come down to the valley for supplies or when they are seeking
      lesser or perhaps even greater solitude than they found among their people in the mountains.
      The exotic &firepeople; from neighboring &desert_kingdom; are often employed as guides and 
      laborers, although some have left their homes to make a living as performers in &arts_city;.
      The fierce humans from the cliffs of &cliffs_nation; are often employed as bodyguards, 
      brawlers, hunters, or any other sort of profession that involves martial prowess. Humans
      from &forest_nation; are significantly more rare, but occasionally a prodigy from the mage's
      academy or a wayward druid will make an appearance.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Dwarves</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Because of the rich underground resources in the country, dwarves are frequently drawn here.
      Most dwarves hail from the mountains in &mountains_nation; to live with their bretheren in the 
      large network of dwarven homes that have been built under the earth. Although most dwarves
      will be living in the outlying areas of the nation, many certainly do find their way to
      the central cities. 
    </para>
    <para>
      Most dwarves will find &market_city; to their liking, as the ever-open markets and vendors 
      offer a great opportunity to sell their wares and find rare materials. Some dwarves with an 
      eye for government or leadership settle in &law_city; and take a post in a guild 
      or legal office. Dwarves in the legal realm are most often acting as representatives of other
      dwarves, and as such many find their way into positions as District Representatives.
    </para>
    <para>
      Dwarves rarely tend to have the patience for as wild a city as &arts_city;.
      However, dwarves seeking a more risky existence, such as warriors from &cliffs_nation;, can 
      find a comfortable living anywhere in the country as bodyguards, hunters, or maybe even 
      in the police force.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Elves</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Elves do come to the central cities in some numbers, but are rarely found elsewhere the nation.
      Drawn by the wealth of craftsmanship and artistic talent, elves come to display their own prowess
      and compare their works to other master artisans'. Because of this, most elves make their home in
      a de-facto elven district in &market_city;, where they can live in a manner closer to home while still 
      reaping the advantages of the city. Elves almost never bother with the political and mercantile
      business that takes place in &law_city;, but sometimes are drawn to the lively music and performances
      in &arts_city;.
    </para>
    <para>
      Most of the elves living in &nation_name; hail from from &forest_nation;, and those that are 
      not craftsmen are most often artists or performers, members of the mage's academy, druids, 
      rangers, or
      clerics of Shelyn. Elves that have chosen a martial path often claim &cliffs_nation; as their 
      home, and they make their living by applying their combat talents wherever they are necessary. 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Gnomes</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      The constant festivites and general excitement of &arts_city; are perfectly suited to the typical
      gnome's mentality. There they delight in taking part in or simply watching performances. While some
      rise to great heights in official groups, most gnomes find great pleasure in being street performers
      or vendors. Gnomes with an eye for business or a craving for the excitement of mercantile 
      enterprises will sometimes venture into &market_city; to try their luck there.
      &law_city; is far to boring and rigid for the majority of Gnomes and they are rarely seen
      there.
    </para>
  </section>
    <section>
    <info>
      <title>Halflings</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      The hubbub and excitement of the central cities are perfectly suited to a halfling's demeanor, and
      they can be found in great numbers in any of the cities. Artisans, shopkeepers, performers, and
      even occasionally politicians, a Halfling's upbeat and amiable attitude is a formidable asset.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Half-Elves</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Half-elves face no discrimination for the mixed origin in any of the central cities, where diversity
      is welcome and omnipresent. Because of this welcoming environment, Half-Elves have flourished in
      the region and many travel from distant lands to come here. Here, their mixed origin plays to their
      advantage, and they are well suited to any role in the cities. However, many heed the call of their
      Elven side and find themselves as either artisans in Crent or performers in Oblectant.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Half-Orcs</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Although diversity is welcomed in the central cities, brutishness and crass are not. Although not
      hated or feared by any means, most Half-Orcs simply do not fit into the lifestyle of these cities,
      and so choose instead to live in the outlying towns and villages of the nation. Those who do choose
      to live the cities tend to make their living as bodyguards for wealthy politicians or merchants, or
      as a part of the police force.
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>