<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
  <!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "../common/shared_entities.xml">
  %sharedents;
]>
<!--
The MIT License (MIT)

Copyright (c) 2014 Robert Winslow Dalpe

Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
-->
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title>Classes in &nation_name;</title>
  </info>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Barbarians</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      The civilized and well-kept lands of &nation_name; are inhospitable to barbarian tribes. 
      Barbarism and brutishness are frowned upon universally across the country, and
      many barbarians will find it a challenge to be welcomed or to fit in. As there are no
      naturally occurring tribes in the valley, most barbarians trace their origins elsewhere on the
      continent. In particular, they thrive in the blazing sands of &desert_kingdom; and
      in the gladiatorial pits of &cliffs_nation;. 
    </para>
    <para>
      In &desert_kingdom;, fire-blooded &firepeople; are the warriors of nomadic tribes who roam 
      the desert, never staying in one place for too long as they consider it their duty to 
      safeguard their home and its culture. Though they may feel the bloodlust of battle, many are 
      pragmatists and some fund the efforts of their tribes by working as mercenaries. Others 
      may be outcasts or seekers of gold and glory looking to start a new life in a land different 
      from what they have known.
    </para>
    <para>
      &cliffs_nation_person; barbarians frequently rise to great ranks in the warrior culture of 
      their homeland. There, where power and determination are revered, barbarians can live akin to
      nobility. However, feats of greatness must be constantly proven, and one can only rise so
      high without a worthy tale of one's own. To this end, many leave &cliffs_nation; to
      travel the continent in search of fame and honor. But for each glorified warrior, there are 
      many defeated ones in his wake, and some among them are barbarians looking to redeem their 
      names in a new land. 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Bards</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      As a cultural capital, &nation_name;&mdash;and in particular the central cities&mdash;holds 
      performance and entertainment in high esteem and demand. One of the central cities, 
      &arts_city;, is completely dedicated to the betterment and enjoyment of the arts, and any
      performer, new or veteran, will find opportunity there. From frenetic street festivals, to
      the studious halls of &arts_college;, to the crystalline elegance of the &amphitheater; 
      amphitheater, there is no limit to the passions of &arts_city;'s citizens. This intensity has 
      even produced a saying known throughout the nation: no great performer will forever die so 
      long as there is music in &arts_city;. 
    </para>
    <para>
      Even outside of &arts_city;, a performer has many opportunities to excel. Politicians, 
      storeowners, and merchant guilds are all keenly aware of the impact a charismatic face can
      have on one's audience, and many seek the services of skilled spokesmen. Travelers, far
      from their homes, find comfort in local song and art even in a land so distant. And a rural
      life may become grim indeed without wanderers who tell tales or sing songs of grand 
      excitement and adventure.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Clerics</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      &nation_name; was founded as part of an Abadarian religious crusade, and its roots are still 
      apparent to this day. Although the nation is not strictly aligned with any one deity, its 
      senate is composed of eighteen representatives from the most influential temples&mdash;be it
      influence through number of worshipers, wealth, or other means. Currently the temples of 
      Abadar, Shelyn, Cayden Cailean, Sarenrae, Pharasma, Iomedae, and Erastil hold senate 
      positions. The temple of Abadar has maintained major power in the city, and from the gilded
      halls of &abadar_temple; in &law_city; it oversees much of the nation's financial and legal
      well-being. Shelyn and Cayden Cailean both have large followings in &arts_city;, and their 
      temples&mdash;&shelyn_temple; and &cc_temple;&mdash;draw tourists and worshippers from
      far and wide.
    </para>
    <para>
      Iomedae's temple is the &police_hq; in &law_city; and much of the police force are devotees.
      Sarenrae, Pharasma, and Erastil enjoy large popular support from all around the nation for
      their public services and good works, but they do not maintain large shrines or temples in
      any one location. Many other faiths have worshippers in &nation_name;, and although they do 
      not hold prominent political power, Desna, Gozreh, Calistria, and Irori all have noteworthy 
      followings in various places around the country.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Druids</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      The bounteous lands of the valley of &valley_name; are full of marvelous phenonmena and natural
      resources, and there is great need for those who would steward those resources correctly. 
      As a result, the druidic population of &nation_name; is not just composed of local druids, but
      also of those who have traveled long distances to experience the wonders of the valley. In
      particular, the nation has a considerable influx of druids from &forest_nation; even those of
      the reclusive &beast_tribes;. Once in the country, druids tend to pursue their own
      goals as wanderers, members of a druidic micro-community, or even as members of larger 
      organizations for&mdash;or perhaps against&mdash;the government.
    </para>
    <para>
      The druidic micro-communities are groups of druids that tend to gather together at sites of
      particular spiritual significance. There, they tend to flora and fauna of the area and ensure
      that the site is preserved against any who would do it harm. The &falls_druids; are especially 
      well known to locals and tourists for their protection of the &falls; area, and are perhaps 
      more famous than the druids would like.
    </para>
    <para>
      Druids that are members of larger organizations tend to work with a temple or the government.
      There they perform local functions such as ensuring that the harbors and rivers are 
      maintained, and giving advance warning for weather. They may also act as members of 
      committees that perform environmental advisories and studies for government projects. Not all
      organizations are so friendly towards the smooth operation of local and national government,
      however. One particularly infamous group, known as &bad_druids;, are publicly a pro-nature
      lobbying group, but are widely known to perform anti-civilization acts such as magically
      weakening the foundations of buildings, defacing directories and road signs, and planting 
      trees in non-designated zones.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Fighters</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Martial prowess is a much sought after skill in &nation_name; and those who are gifted will
      find many opportunities to display their strengths. Although there is no formal army, the
      &police; is always looking for those of sharp mind and strong arm to help keep the 
      peace. Because of their limited manpower, the police have learned to fight smart, and they
      employ a wide range of skilled combat researchers and engineers to develop new tactics and
      equipment. Fighters looking to earn more than the govnerment is willing to pay might prefer
      to take on the role of bodyguard or strongman for a wealthy noble or shopowner. Others still
      may prefer to take a riskier path and bring their feats to the stage as combat performers
      &mdash;masquerading their deadly arts as performance pieces. Outside of the central cities, 
      those skilled in combat and with good knowledge of the land excel as hunters or guards for 
      villages and trade caravans. 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Monks</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Monks seeking purification and enlightenment through order and community may find themselves 
      at home in the central cities. There they have the opportunity to participate as good 
      samaritans via public works. There is only one official monk sect in the nation, the 
      &monk_sect;. They are a sect sworn to poverty and truth. In addition to the good works they 
      do for the communities around the country, they also act as a counter-lobby to the economic 
      elite of &nation_name;. Although there is only one official sect, many of the librarians in
      &library; are monks who worship Irori. Regardless of affiliation, martial skill and spiritual 
      leadership are valued traits all around the nation. Whether as enforcers for the &police;,
      covert bodyguards, performers, or guides for those who wander from the path to enlightenment,
      a monk will not find herself without a purpose for long.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Paladins</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Although the nation was founded as a result of a crusade, it has grown so prosperous and successful
      that paladins are not seen as needed by national officials. However, because of the strong religious
      presence in the nation, many paladins still find themselves drawn here to advance their causes. A
      paladin should be cautious, however, as in the court room the nation's laws will always trump any
      conflicting religious edict.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Rangers</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Rangers are abundant in the nation, but less frequently found in the central cities, save when they
      travel there to drop off goods from the wilderness or to seek out new hunts and bounties.
      Rangers who do choose to make a living in the city often do so as members of the police or as
      privately employed bounty hunters. In outlying areas, a ranger will find many places to call his 
      home.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Rogues</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Although the central cities are lawful and safe places, a rogue's talents are nonetheless very useful to
      the elite of the cities. Merchants and politicians alike can always find a use for someone with
      quick hands and silent feet. Outside the central cities, non-criminal rogues are less common and
      most frequently make their livings as trappers or hunters.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Sorcerers</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      Sorcerers may not benefit from the vast libraries and universities of the nation, but they may still
      enjoy its wild atmospheres and the opportunities provided here. Sorcerers with the skill for panache and
      performance may find themselves drawn to &arts_city;, while those who wish to put their magical 
      abilities to use to further their own wealth or careers may find &law_city; or &market_city; more to their 
      liking.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <info>
      <title>Wizards</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      The vast libraries and combined cultural knowledge of the central cities are a great resource to
      many wizards, and none will struggle to find employment here. Whether as part of a merchant's 
      retinue, as an appraiser of magical goods, or a craftsman in his own right, magical talent is always
      useful in the nation.
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>