<authorgroup xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <author xml:id="author1">
    <personname>
      <firstname>Robert</firstname>
      <othername>Winslow</othername>
      <surname>Dalpe</surname>
    </personname>
    <email>rwdalpe@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <author xml:id="author2">
    <personname>
      <firstname>Ashlyn</firstname>
      <surname>Warren</surname>
    </personname>
  </author>
</authorgroup>
<legalnotice xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <title>Legal Information</title>
  <para>
    This content uses trademarks and/or copyrights owned by Paizo Inc., which are used under 
    Paizo's Community Use Policy. We are expressly prohibited from charging you to use or access
    this content. This content is not published, endorsed, or specifically approved by Paizo 
    Inc. For more information about Paizo's Community Use Policy, please visit 
    <link xlink:href="http://paizo.com/communityuse"/>. For more information about Paizo Inc. 
    and Paizo products, please visit <link xlink:href="http://paizo.com"/>.
  </para>
  <para>
    The content of this book is compliant with the Open Game License (OGL). The
    OGL can be found in <xref linkend="ogl" />. The following items are hereby 
    identified as Product Identity, as defined in the Open Game License version 
    1.0a, Section 1(e), and are not Open Content: artwork. Any content used in 
    this book under Paizo's Community Use Policy is owned by Paizo Inc. and 
    should not be considered Open Game Content unless otherwise specified by 
    Paizo Inc. All other content in this book is hereby designated as Open Game Content 
    as defined in the Open Gaming License version 1.0a Section 1(d). No portion 
    of this work other than the material designated as Open Game Content may be 
    reproduced in any form without written permission. To learn more about the 
    Open Game License and the d20 System License, please visit 
    <link xlink:href="http://www.wizards.com/default.asp?x=d20/article/srdarchive"/>.
  </para>
  <para>
    The source code used to generate the textual content of this book is available at 
    <link xlink:href="https://github.com/rwdalpe/two-graves"/> and is available under the
    <xref linkend="agpl" xrefstyle="select: title"/>.
  </para>
</legalnotice>
<pubdate xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <?dbtimestamp format="Y-m-d H:M:S"?>
</pubdate>
<printhistory xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
  <para>
    This is a living document that may undergo changes. The latest date of
    modification is shown above. To see a detailed explanation of changes 
    between releases, please visit 
    <link xlink:href="{changelog_link}">the Changelog</link> 
    or view the git commit history at 
    <link xlink:href="https://github.com/rwdalpe/two-graves"/>.
  </para>
</printhistory>